<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Sam Feldstein&#39;s Notebook</title>
  <subtitle>Sam Feldstein&#39;s digital notebook.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/" />
  <updated>2025-02-13T17:41:58Z</updated>
  <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Sam Feldstein</name>
    <email>samuelfeldstein@proton.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Start a Blog for Free</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-start-a-blog-for-free/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T17:41:58Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-start-a-blog-for-free/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Substack&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Micro.blog&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A website of your own&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title></title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/w/" />
    <updated>2025-02-07T19:56:30Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/w/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Pay Attention</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T18:58:14Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If something is worth doing, it&#39;s worth doing well, and nothing can be done well without attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you pay attention? Stop multitasking. Focus on one activity at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attention comprises two parts: aim and observation. You aim for an outcome, and you observe what works and what doesn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Do Things Well</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-do-things-well/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T18:53:09Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-do-things-well/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing things well is a skill,&lt;/strong&gt;, and therefore takes practice. So if you want to practice, it&#39;s good to believe that &lt;strong&gt;if something is worth doing, it&#39;s worth doing well&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can&#39;t do things well without paying &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/&quot;&gt;attention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Focus on one task at a time, whatever it is. It could be folding laundry. Think about what you&#39;re trying to achieve, observe what works and what doesn&#39;t, then course correct. Rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EFL</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/efl/" />
    <updated>2025-02-03T20:24:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/efl/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do it while you travel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remote option.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve teaching skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work matters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Find work&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;https://www.eslcafe.com&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/TEFL/wiki/index/#wiki_getting_started&quot;&gt;r/TEFL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eslcafe.com&quot;&gt;Dave&#39;s ESL Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>West Coast Swing Cirriculum</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/west-coast-swing-cirriculum/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T23:58:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/west-coast-swing-cirriculum/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teach steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, break the six counts into three stages. Each stage comprises two beats. The stages are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The leader gets out of the way.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Something happens.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anchor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Astro</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/astro/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T16:58:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/astro/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://get.supportsquid.ink&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Meaning of Life</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/meaning-of-life/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T05:27:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/meaning-of-life/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we had nothing else to worry about, wouldn&#39;t we be concerned with making life as fun as possible?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every innovation means to solve a problem. What if there were no problems? Then what would the problem be? To elevate experience. To combat ennui.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in America and the First World are already at this point. They don&#39;t really have much to worry about. They might not be rich, but they can complain about how expensive everything is while eating a $23 hamburger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Serious Man</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/" />
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:09:20Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some who contend that kindness is irrational because it isn&#39;t self-interested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I can&#39;t decide which is more insulting: the suggestion that kindness can&#39;t be justified or the assumption that it has to be justified in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put reason and ethics at odds does both a disservice. Reason becomes something unethical, and ethics becomes something unreasonable. What I appreciate about Judaism is that it teaches us that reason and ethics are not only compatible but mutually inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In any case, who says kindness isn&#39;t self-interested? I&#39;m kind because I&#39;m interested in living in a kind world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;But an action&#39;s reasonability depends on your goal. Regarding ethics, reasonability depends on your vision of paradise. If your paradise doesn&#39;t include Jews, it&#39;s easy to &quot;reason&quot; your way to Auschwitz.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rational position is one you can explain (&lt;em&gt;explain,&lt;/em&gt; not &lt;em&gt;explain away&lt;/em&gt;), and a commitment to goodness can be easily explained so long as you know what kind of world you&#39;d like to live in. I don&#39;t know about you, but the world I&#39;d like to live in is filled with kind people. If that&#39;s the goal, then it makes sense to be kind. Could you ask for a better rationale?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evil&#39;s prevalence &lt;em&gt;makes&lt;/em&gt; goodness rational.&lt;/strong&gt; Every kindness tips the scales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And even if I can&#39;t find a good reason to be kind, I&#39;ll settle for a good excuse: Kindness makes life better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to make a rational decision, we have to know what kind of world we&#39;re aiming for. That&#39;s easy: It&#39;s the world we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Larry is nice. He&#39;s humble. He has principles. He gives people the benefit of the doubt. He believes his wife when she says she and Sy haven&#39;t slept together. A world of Larrys wouldn&#39;t be so bad, though we might not get much done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Atheism</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/atheism/" />
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:05:03Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/atheism/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Herman Cohen said that Judaism discovered the idea of humanity in the stranger. It seems obvious in retrospect, but even the best ideas (seatbelts?) have to be invented. So maybe God was just a palatable delivery mechanism for this idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So long as our shared humanity isn&#39;t reason enough to inspire kindness, we can&#39;t consider ourselves mature as a species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t only ever do the right thing because we&#39;re told to. At some point we need to adopt these moral principles as our own, and stand by them for their own sake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This doesn&#39;t hard. &lt;strong&gt;If we want to live in a kind world, then we should be kind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of &lt;em&gt;love your neighbor as yourself&lt;/em&gt; is that it&#39;s self-justifying. We don&#39;t need a godhead to take this moral imperative seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s true that people&#39;s visions of paradise will differ, but that&#39;s true whether anybody believes in God or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If someone asks why they should be kind, what&#39;s the more convincing answer? &lt;em&gt;Because God said so&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;because that&#39;s how you&#39;d like to be treated?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are citizens of the world, and therefore responsible for making it. You can&#39;t escape this responsibility, even if you choose to shirk. Your actions have consequences whether you believe that or not. You don&#39;t get to just decide you don&#39;t matter, because your actions affect other people, and therefore they always matter. &lt;em&gt;I don&#39;t matter&lt;/em&gt; is an excuse to be ethically lazy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>