<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Sam Feldstein&#39;s Notebook</title>
  <subtitle>Sam Feldstein&#39;s digital notebook.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/" />
  <updated>2025-02-04T18:58:14Z</updated>
  <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Sam Feldstein</name>
    <email>samuelfeldstein@proton.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Pay Attention</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T18:58:14Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If something is worth doing, it&#39;s worth doing well, and nothing can be done well without attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you pay attention? Stop multitasking. Focus on one activity at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attention comprises two parts: aim and observation. You aim for an outcome, and you observe what works and what doesn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Do Things Well</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-do-things-well/" />
    <updated>2025-02-04T18:53:09Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-do-things-well/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing things well is a skill,&lt;/strong&gt;, and therefore takes practice. So if you want to practice, it&#39;s good to believe that &lt;strong&gt;if something is worth doing, it&#39;s worth doing well&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can&#39;t do things well without paying &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/how-to-pay-attention/&quot;&gt;attention&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Focus on one task at a time, whatever it is. It could be folding laundry. Think about what you&#39;re trying to achieve, observe what works and what doesn&#39;t, then course correct. Rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TEFL</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/tefl/" />
    <updated>2025-02-03T20:24:32Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/tefl/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do it while you travel.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remote option.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve teaching skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Work matters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/TEFL/wiki/index/#wiki_getting_started&quot;&gt;r/TEFL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>West Coast Swing Cirriculum</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/west-coast-swing-cirriculum/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T23:58:53Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/west-coast-swing-cirriculum/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teach steps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, break the six counts into three stages. Each stage comprises two beats. The stages are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The leader steps out of the slot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Something happens.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The leader steps back into the slot and we anchor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>West Coast and Symmetry</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dance-as-symmetry/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T23:56:33Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dance-as-symmetry/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you dance with someone, &lt;strong&gt;you become a system&lt;/strong&gt;. The aforementioned aliens should not immediately understand that they are looking at two distinct organisms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Systems rely on symmetry. When two forces act on each other in equal proportion, you get symmetry. Think of a star and a planet. The planet orbits the star. If the star&#39;s gravity were too strong, it&#39;d suck the planet into its core. If the planet were moving too fast, it&#39;d fly off into space. Neither happens, because the relationship between the star&#39;s gravity and the planet&#39;s speed is symmetrical. It is balanced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise with dance. The leader is the star, because they remain more or less centered, while the follower &quot;orbits&quot; them. The follower is the planet, because they do all the spinning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I think what you have to do is attune yourself to your center of gravity, then attune your center of gravity to your partner&#39;s center of gravity. If you can do that, you get symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you attune yourself to your center of gravity? Well, first you have to find it. I&#39;m guessing&#39;s everybody&#39;s center will be in a slightly different place. Mine hovers just below my solarplexis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you find your center, you dance from it. It&#39;s tempting to dance from your feet, because that&#39;s how we walk; you move your foot first, then your body follows through. In dance, it&#39;s the other way around. Instead of moving your feet first, &lt;strong&gt;you move your center first, and simply let your feet come with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Astro</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/astro/" />
    <updated>2025-02-02T16:58:28Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/astro/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://get.supportsquid.ink&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Meaning of Life</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/meaning-of-life/" />
    <updated>2025-01-29T05:27:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/meaning-of-life/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we had nothing else to worry about, wouldn&#39;t we be concerned with making life as fun as possible?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every innovation means to solve a problem. What if there were no problems? Then what would the problem be? To elevate experience. To combat ennui.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in America and the First World are already at this point. They don&#39;t really have much to worry about. They might not be rich, but they can complain about how expensive everything is while eating a $23 hamburger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Serious Man</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/" />
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:09:20Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some who contend that kindness is irrational because it isn&#39;t self-interested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I can&#39;t decide which is more insulting: the suggestion that kindness can&#39;t be justified or the assumption that it has to be justified in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put reason and ethics at odds does both a disservice. Reason becomes something unethical, and ethics becomes something unreasonable. What I appreciate about Judaism is that it teaches us that reason and ethics are not only compatible but mutually inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In any case, who says kindness isn&#39;t self-interested? I&#39;m kind because I&#39;m interested in living in a kind world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;But an action&#39;s reasonability depends on your goal. Regarding ethics, reasonability depends on your vision of paradise. If your paradise doesn&#39;t include Jews, it&#39;s easy to &quot;reason&quot; your way to Auschwitz.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rational position is one you can explain (&lt;em&gt;explain,&lt;/em&gt; not &lt;em&gt;explain away&lt;/em&gt;), and a commitment to goodness can be easily explained so long as you know what kind of world you&#39;d like to live in. I don&#39;t know about you, but the world I&#39;d like to live in is filled with kind people. If that&#39;s the goal, then it makes sense to be kind. Could you ask for a better rationale?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evil&#39;s prevalence &lt;em&gt;makes&lt;/em&gt; goodness rational.&lt;/strong&gt; Every kindness tips the scales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And even if I can&#39;t find a good reason to be kind, I&#39;ll settle for a good excuse: Kindness makes life better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to make a rational decision, we have to know what kind of world we&#39;re aiming for. That&#39;s easy: It&#39;s the world we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Larry is nice. He&#39;s humble. He has principles. He gives people the benefit of the doubt. He believes his wife when she says she and Sy haven&#39;t slept together. A world of Larrys wouldn&#39;t be so bad, though we might not get much done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Atheism</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/atheism/" />
    <updated>2025-01-28T00:05:03Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/atheism/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Herman Cohen said that Judaism discovered the idea of humanity in the stranger. It seems obvious in retrospect, but even the best ideas (seatbelts?) have to be invented. So maybe God was just a palatable delivery mechanism for this idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So long as our shared humanity isn&#39;t reason enough to inspire kindness, we can&#39;t consider ourselves mature as a species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t only ever do the right thing because we&#39;re told to. At some point we need to adopt these moral principles as our own, and stand by them for their own sake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This doesn&#39;t hard. &lt;strong&gt;If we want to live in a kind world, then we should be kind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of &lt;em&gt;love your neighbor as yourself&lt;/em&gt; is that it&#39;s self-justifying. We don&#39;t need a godhead to take this moral imperative seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s true that people&#39;s visions of paradise will differ, but that&#39;s true whether anybody believes in God or not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If someone asks why they should be kind, what&#39;s the more convincing answer? &lt;em&gt;Because God said so&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;because that&#39;s how you&#39;d like to be treated?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are citizens of the world, and therefore responsible for making it. You can&#39;t escape this responsibility, even if you choose to shirk. Your actions have consequences whether you believe that or not. You don&#39;t get to just decide you don&#39;t matter, because your actions affect other people, and therefore they always matter. &lt;em&gt;I don&#39;t matter&lt;/em&gt; is an excuse to be ethically lazy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dvar Coen: Kindess as Duh-Statement</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dvar-coen/" />
    <updated>2025-01-26T19:17:44Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dvar-coen/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the record, I told Mom she could skip this introduction if she wanted to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I lived with my folks in Bondurant for three months at the beginning of last year. While I was home I started going with Mom to the Rabbi&#39;s classes. I was slated to move away again in April, and before I left Neal asked me if I had any requests for a topic. I told him I&#39;d love a class on &lt;em&gt;A Serious Man&lt;/em&gt;, one of my favorite movies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, we didn&#39;t get &lt;em&gt;A Serious Man&lt;/em&gt; that time. What we did get was a two-hour lecture on the merits of circumcision, based on the Rabbi&#39;s Master&#39;s thesis. A truncated thesis on my truncated penis, as though my missing foreskin &lt;em&gt;wasn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; number one on the list of things I try not to think about. (Where is it now? What&#39;s it doing? Does it have a family? Is it happy? Does it ever think about me? Why doesn&#39;t it write?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So when Mom mentioned the other day that Neal had screened &lt;em&gt;A Serious Man&lt;/em&gt; in Adult Ed, I was understandably outraged. The &lt;em&gt;chutzpah!&lt;/em&gt; And so, being well out of striking distance, I decided to instead write in with some brief thoughts about the movie. For your consideration, this is my dvar Coen:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dvar Coen&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite scene in &lt;em&gt;A Serious Man&lt;/em&gt; is the Goy&#39;s Teeth parable. For those who haven&#39;t committed the entire movie to memory, that&#39;s the story told by the second Rabbi (Nachtner, the bald one), about a Jewish dentist named Sussman who finds a message carved into the back of a goy&#39;s teeth. The message, which is written in Hebrew, reads, &lt;em&gt;Help me, save me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Larry&#39;s wife is having an affair, one of his students is trying to bribe him, and someone is writing letters defaming him to the tenure committee. Larry wants to know what it all means, and he&#39;s come to Nachtner for answers. Nachtner tells him about the goy&#39;s teeth to illustrate that sometimes questions don&#39;t have answers. He concludes thus: &lt;em&gt;What could such a sign mean?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s Nachtner&#39;s punchline. But the &lt;em&gt;scene&#39;s&lt;/em&gt; punchline comes a moment later after Larry demands that Nachtner tell him what he told Sussman. Nachtner seems to think it&#39;s beside the point, but he tells Larry anyway: &lt;em&gt;The teeth? We don&#39;t know. Signs from HaShem? Don&#39;t know. Helping others? Couldn&#39;t hurt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nachtner delivers the line with a nonchalance that I used to think was incompatible with kindness as a commandment. Maybe it is. But nonchalance is not incompatible with kindness as a duh-statement, and &lt;em&gt;helping others, couldn&#39;t hurt&lt;/em&gt; is the duh-statement to end all duh-statements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I sound flippant, it&#39;s only because I see great value in taking this idea for granted. As Nachtner contends (with infuriating serenity), we can&#39;t know everything. But there is at least one thing we can know; not &lt;em&gt;believe,&lt;/em&gt; not take on faith, but &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; for a certainty: Helping others is good. We don&#39;t have to bite our nails over it. We can just get to work. If this isn&#39;t the answer to every unanswerable question, it&#39;s at least a sound response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I&#39;ve always admired about Judaism is that it is for all its palaver a pragmatic system of thought primarily concerned with the here and now. What we know is more important than what we don&#39;t know. What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; is more important than what &lt;em&gt;might be&lt;/em&gt;. Unanswerable questions should be asked but not dwelt on at the expense of our sacred duh-statements and the good we might do in service to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The teeth? We don&#39;t know. Signs from HaShem? Don&#39;t know. Helping others? Couldn&#39;t hurt.&lt;/em&gt; This is the whole movie. The rest is commentary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>