<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Sam Feldstein&#39;s Notebook</title>
  <subtitle>Sam Feldstein&#39;s digital notebook.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/" />
  <updated>2025-01-17T16:33:30Z</updated>
  <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Sam Feldstein</name>
    <email>samuelfeldstein@proton.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Craft and Purpose</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/craft-and-purpose/" />
    <updated>2025-01-17T16:33:30Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/craft-and-purpose/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can craft itself lend a sense of purpose? I used to think so. I used to think I could derive purpose from making things for the sake of it. Now I think this is wrong. There are plenty of things I like doing and find satisfying. Taking photos, for instance. I like taking photos, and I&#39;m proud of many of the photos I&#39;ve taken. But could I spend all day taking photos and be satisfied? No. Because while I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; photography, I don&#39;t feel that it matters much. It doesn&#39;t give me a sense of purpose. The best photographers in the world probably feel differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for me, the craft itself doesn&#39;t lend a send of purpose. &lt;strong&gt;The purpose comes from the application of the craft:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;m not coding just to code. I&#39;m coding to build something I can use. I&#39;m not writing just to write. I&#39;m writing to figure something out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The said, the work itself matters too. I didn&#39;t enjoy helping my mom attach the snowplow to her truck nearly as much as helping her with the court case research. &lt;strong&gt;So the work needs to be engaging.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what you&#39;re looking for is &lt;strong&gt;maximum engagement + maximum importance&lt;/strong&gt;. But in lieu of that ideal situation, &lt;strong&gt;the work either has to be engaging enough to make up for a lack of importance, or important enough to make up for a lack of engagement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, writing fiction isn&#39;t important enough to me to make up how not-engaging it is. By contrast, coding is engaging, but when I do it for anyone other than myself or someone I care about, it doesn&#39;t feel important enough to be worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Airbnb Arbitrage</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/airbnb-arbitrage/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T18:42:58Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/airbnb-arbitrage/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sidehustlenation.com/rental-arbitrage/&quot;&gt;Side Hustle Nation: Rental Arbitrage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Short Term Rentals</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/short-term-rentals/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T18:38:52Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/short-term-rentals/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look for major upcoming events (1-2 years out) and buy property in those cities. I got this idea from Ryan, who has a friend who does this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Easy Hard Work</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/easy-hard-work/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T18:14:37Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/easy-hard-work/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some types of work are easier than others. Building websites is much easier than writing fiction. It&#39;s not that it&#39;s &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; work, insofar as it&#39;s quite time-consuming, but it&#39;s easier to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; the work. I don&#39;t have to force myself to build websites, at least when I&#39;m doing it for myself. By contrast, I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; had to force myself to write. Building websites is engaging in a way that writing fiction just isn&#39;t. They&#39;re both work. But &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; the work in one case is easy, and in the other the bulk of effort goes to just trying to keep myself at the desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds pretty good, but I have my doubts. What if some work is just that much harder than other work. I&#39;ve noted before that building websites almost feels like a video game at times, I think because it has a innate feedback loop that writing lacks. You write some code, and the result pops up in the browser. You instantly know if it&#39;s working, and there&#39;s great satisfaction to be taken when it is. Not so with writing. You can only really tell if it&#39;s working once you&#39;ve had some time away from it, and even then it&#39;s not a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But am I taking this feeling for granted? Maybe it&#39;s not the case for everyone. And if it&#39;s not, then shouldn&#39;t be take our kicks where we get them? If someone else described cooking the same way, I wouldn&#39;t be able to agree. Cooking is fun and satisyfing, but not nearly as engaging as coding. But if someone found cooking as engaging as I find coding, I&#39;d say that person is cut out to be a chef.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, it&#39;s not that simple. Because I only find coding that engaging when I care about the project. I had fun builidng my personal site. Likewise with my mom&#39;s website. But my freelance gigs aren&#39;t nearly as fun, and I think this is because I just don&#39;t care as much. The emotional investment isn&#39;t there. Which tells that the emotional investment is necessary to doing good work. That might seem obvious, but I&#39;ve also spent a lot of time trying to detach myself emotionally from a given project becasue I was convinced that toom uch investment was a bad thing, because it tied too much of your self worth to the project and so engendered self-consciousness. If I could just become a stoic craftsman, then maybe I could do something interseting, free from fear and doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be something to that, and I doubt there&#39;s one way to go about it. Probably you just have to find the thing that works for you. If you can&#39;t get there without the emotional volatility, embrace it. If you can only get there by quashing the feelings, crush them mercilessly. Usually you can do this with another feeling. Quash doubt with anger, for instance. That takes an immense amount of effort, which is probably why writing is so exhausting. You&#39;re trying to keep a lid on the self-doubt while perfecting a craft at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why people like Ray Bradbury tell you not to think. Stephen King says to write fast enough to outrun the self doubt. Another way to think about it is to do your best to try to get absorbed in the work to such a degree that you and your feelinsg disappers, and all that&#39;s left is the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which comes back to engagement. The more engaging work is, the easier it is to fall into it, so to speak. But choosing activities solely based on how engaging they are seemsl ike a bad idea. If you did that, you&#39;d just play video games all day. That said, I don&#39;t find video games nearly as engaging as I used to. So this, like all things, seems subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broader question though is is it wrong to choose work based on how engaging it is? Am I wrong to choose websites over writing because I find building websites so much more engaging than writing? I don&#39;t see why that should be a problem. If you can find something useful to do that you don&#39;t have to force yousrelf to do, that seems like as close a recipe to career happiness as you can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&#39;s multivariate. The work either has to be engaging enough or important enough to make up for it. Writing simply isn&#39;t important enough to me to make up how not engaging it is. Coding is engaging, but when I do for anyone other than myself or someone I care about, suddenly it&#39;s not important enough to be worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s why I want to work for myself. Maybe I&#39;m selfish, but I find it very difficult to summon the will to work for other people. I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it. I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; done it. And I&#39;ve worked hard. But it&#39;s no way to spend a life. The solution is to work for myself, or possibly with a friend. I&#39;m pretty sure that&#39;s as close to a satisfying career as I&#39;m ever going to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective Learning</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/learning/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T20:51:39Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/learning/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo_Guru&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Self-Hatred</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/self-hatred/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T06:18:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/self-hatred/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hated myself for the first twenty-five years of my life, give or take. (I still do sometimes, but it&#39;s &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better.) I thought I was pathetic. I struggled to do things that in my imagination came naturally to other people. Talking to girls, for instance. Or talking to anybody, for that matter. For years, I could not for the life of me hold a conversation. I tried to pay attention, to come up with interesting things to say, but inevitably I&#39;d feel the conversation dying on the vine and I&#39;d know it was my fault and I wouldn&#39;t mean to but I couldn&#39;t help but kill it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to study other people and how they talked to each other, though I don&#39;t think I did it with a critical eye so much as an envious one, thinking to myself &lt;em&gt;I wish I could do that. What&#39;s wrong with me that I can&#39;t?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&#39;re allowed to have a low opinion of yourself as long as you come by it honestly.&lt;/strong&gt; But at some point self-pity becomes self-serving. It gives you an out. I can&#39;t be bothered to put in the effort? Great, I&#39;m too stupid to figure it out anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Discomfort</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/discomfort/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T06:07:21Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/discomfort/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always stayed in my comfort zone. I never did anything hard, out of some combination of fear and laziness. I never liked that about myself, but it took me a long time to do anything about it. I basically spent the first twenty-five years of my life working up the nerve to do anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every decision I&#39;ve made in the last year (Workaway, taking up dance) has been a direct assault on my lack of confidence. This is a theme for me. &lt;strong&gt;Pretty much every real decision I&#39;ve made I&#39;ve made out of a desire to change something I don&#39;t like about myself.&lt;/strong&gt; And I have to say, I&#39;m pretty happy with the person I&#39;ve become in the last two years. He&#39;s much more confident than he used to be. He&#39;s friendly. He&#39;s learned, somewhat, how to set the tone of an interaction. He&#39;s learned to become aware of other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judaism Resources</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/judaism-resources/" />
    <updated>2025-01-14T20:55:25Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/judaism-resources/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sefaria.org/texts&quot;&gt;Sefaria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org&quot;&gt;Jewish Virtual Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jeffbenner.net&quot;&gt;Jeff Benner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Honesty</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/honesty/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T21:52:33Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/honesty/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you never piss anyone off, you probably aren&#39;t speaking your mind enough. (That said, I don&#39;t admire people who enjoy pissing people off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you aren&#39;t honest, you&#39;ll never connect with people the way you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Purpose</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/purpose/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T19:14:09Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/purpose/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;style id=&quot;MJX-SVG-styles&quot;&gt;
mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] {
  direction: ltr;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] &gt; svg {
  overflow: visible;
  min-height: 1px;
  min-width: 1px;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] &gt; svg a {
  fill: blue;
  stroke: blue;
}

mjx-assistive-mml {
  position: absolute !important;
  top: 0px;
  left: 0px;
  clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);
  padding: 1px 0px 0px 0px !important;
  border: 0px !important;
  display: block !important;
  width: auto !important;
  overflow: hidden !important;
  -webkit-touch-callout: none;
  -webkit-user-select: none;
  -khtml-user-select: none;
  -moz-user-select: none;
  -ms-user-select: none;
  user-select: none;
}

mjx-assistive-mml[display=&quot;block&quot;] {
  width: 100% !important;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][display=&quot;true&quot;] {
  display: block;
  text-align: center;
  margin: 1em 0;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][display=&quot;true&quot;][width=&quot;full&quot;] {
  display: flex;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][justify=&quot;left&quot;] {
  text-align: left;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][justify=&quot;right&quot;] {
  text-align: right;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;merror&quot;] &gt; g {
  fill: red;
  stroke: red;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;merror&quot;] &gt; rect[data-background] {
  fill: yellow;
  stroke: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; line[data-line], svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; line[data-line] {
  stroke-width: 70px;
  fill: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; rect[data-frame], svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; rect[data-frame] {
  stroke-width: 70px;
  fill: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; .mjx-dashed, svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; .mjx-dashed {
  stroke-dasharray: 140;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; .mjx-dotted, svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; .mjx-dotted {
  stroke-linecap: round;
  stroke-dasharray: 0,140;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; g &gt; svg {
  overflow: visible;
}

[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] mjx-tool {
  display: inline-block;
  position: relative;
  width: 0;
  height: 0;
}

[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] mjx-tool &gt; mjx-tip {
  position: absolute;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
}

mjx-tool &gt; mjx-tip {
  display: inline-block;
  padding: .2em;
  border: 1px solid #888;
  font-size: 70%;
  background-color: #F8F8F8;
  color: black;
  box-shadow: 2px 2px 5px #AAAAAA;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;maction&quot;][data-toggle] {
  cursor: pointer;
}

mjx-status {
  display: block;
  position: fixed;
  left: 1em;
  bottom: 1em;
  min-width: 25%;
  padding: .2em .4em;
  border: 1px solid #888;
  font-size: 90%;
  background-color: #F8F8F8;
  color: black;
}

foreignObject[data-mjx-xml] {
  font-family: initial;
  line-height: normal;
  overflow: visible;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] path[data-c], mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] use[data-c] {
  stroke-width: 3;
}
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To live a fulfilling life, you need a sense of purpose.&lt;/strong&gt; I think this is what people mean when they talk about &quot;finding their place in the world&quot; or &quot;living a meaningful life.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s a sense of purpose? I suppose this depends on the person, so all I can do here is answer for myself. &lt;strong&gt;So for me, &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt; is a sense that I&#39;ve made a difference, that I&#39;ve done something that matters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when do/have I felt that way? Here&#39;s a list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I helped my mom research a court case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I help new dancers learn the basics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I organized a writers&#39; group in grad school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I give feedback on friends&#39; writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I taught horseback riding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I built my website and notebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of those examples involve working with people. And the goal of each collaboration seems to serve the other person. So maybe &lt;strong&gt;I prefer helping to being helped.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure whether this would translate to collaborating in service to a mutual goal (eg, cofounding a company). I haven&#39;t done much of that. But I&#39;m curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these (writers group) involves &lt;strong&gt;community-building.&lt;/strong&gt; Haven&#39;t done much of that either. I do like hosting parties, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the projects I&#39;ve worked on that gave me the greatest sense of purpose involved &lt;strong&gt;engaging collaborative work that also felt important&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe the formula is something like: &lt;em&gt;Engaging work + collaboration + importance = a sense of purpose.&lt;/em&gt; Or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;mjx-container class=&quot;MathJax&quot; jax=&quot;SVG&quot; style=&quot;position: relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg style=&quot;vertical-align: -0.186ex;&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;14.836ex&quot; height=&quot;1.781ex&quot; role=&quot;img&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 -705 6557.4 787&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;0&quot; transform=&quot;scale(1,-1)&quot;&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;math&quot;&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D438&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D438&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(986.2,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;2B&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(1986.4,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D436&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D436&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(2968.7,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;2B&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(3968.9,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D43C&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D43C&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(4750.7,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;3D&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-3D&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(5806.4,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D443&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D443&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;mjx-assistive-mml unselectable=&quot;on&quot; display=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;&lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/mjx-assistive-mml&gt;&lt;/mjx-container&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;svg style=&quot;display: none;&quot; id=&quot;MJX-SVG-global-cache&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D438&quot; d=&quot;M492 213Q472 213 472 226Q472 230 477 250T482 285Q482 316 461 323T364 330H312Q311 328 277 192T243 52Q243 48 254 48T334 46Q428 46 458 48T518 61Q567 77 599 117T670 248Q680 270 683 272Q690 274 698 274Q718 274 718 261Q613 7 608 2Q605 0 322 0H133Q31 0 31 11Q31 13 34 25Q38 41 42 43T65 46Q92 46 125 49Q139 52 144 61Q146 66 215 342T285 622Q285 629 281 629Q273 632 228 634H197Q191 640 191 642T193 659Q197 676 203 680H757Q764 676 764 669Q764 664 751 557T737 447Q735 440 717 440H705Q698 445 698 453L701 476Q704 500 704 528Q704 558 697 578T678 609T643 625T596 632T532 634H485Q397 633 392 631Q388 629 386 622Q385 619 355 499T324 377Q347 376 372 376H398Q464 376 489 391T534 472Q538 488 540 490T557 493Q562 493 565 493T570 492T572 491T574 487T577 483L544 351Q511 218 508 216Q505 213 492 213Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot; d=&quot;M56 237T56 250T70 270H369V420L370 570Q380 583 389 583Q402 583 409 568V270H707Q722 262 722 250T707 230H409V-68Q401 -82 391 -82H389H387Q375 -82 369 -68V230H70Q56 237 56 250Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D436&quot; d=&quot;M50 252Q50 367 117 473T286 641T490 704Q580 704 633 653Q642 643 648 636T656 626L657 623Q660 623 684 649Q691 655 699 663T715 679T725 690L740 705H746Q760 705 760 698Q760 694 728 561Q692 422 692 421Q690 416 687 415T669 413H653Q647 419 647 422Q647 423 648 429T650 449T651 481Q651 552 619 605T510 659Q484 659 454 652T382 628T299 572T226 479Q194 422 175 346T156 222Q156 108 232 58Q280 24 350 24Q441 24 512 92T606 240Q610 253 612 255T628 257Q648 257 648 248Q648 243 647 239Q618 132 523 55T319 -22Q206 -22 128 53T50 252Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D43C&quot; d=&quot;M43 1Q26 1 26 10Q26 12 29 24Q34 43 39 45Q42 46 54 46H60Q120 46 136 53Q137 53 138 54Q143 56 149 77T198 273Q210 318 216 344Q286 624 286 626Q284 630 284 631Q274 637 213 637H193Q184 643 189 662Q193 677 195 680T209 683H213Q285 681 359 681Q481 681 487 683H497Q504 676 504 672T501 655T494 639Q491 637 471 637Q440 637 407 634Q393 631 388 623Q381 609 337 432Q326 385 315 341Q245 65 245 59Q245 52 255 50T307 46H339Q345 38 345 37T342 19Q338 6 332 0H316Q279 2 179 2Q143 2 113 2T65 2T43 1Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-N-3D&quot; d=&quot;M56 347Q56 360 70 367H707Q722 359 722 347Q722 336 708 328L390 327H72Q56 332 56 347ZM56 153Q56 168 72 173H708Q722 163 722 153Q722 140 707 133H70Q56 140 56 153Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D443&quot; d=&quot;M287 628Q287 635 230 637Q206 637 199 638T192 648Q192 649 194 659Q200 679 203 681T397 683Q587 682 600 680Q664 669 707 631T751 530Q751 453 685 389Q616 321 507 303Q500 302 402 301H307L277 182Q247 66 247 59Q247 55 248 54T255 50T272 48T305 46H336Q342 37 342 35Q342 19 335 5Q330 0 319 0Q316 0 282 1T182 2Q120 2 87 2T51 1Q33 1 33 11Q33 13 36 25Q40 41 44 43T67 46Q94 46 127 49Q141 52 146 61Q149 65 218 339T287 628ZM645 554Q645 567 643 575T634 597T609 619T560 635Q553 636 480 637Q463 637 445 637T416 636T404 636Q391 635 386 627Q384 621 367 550T332 412T314 344Q314 342 395 342H407H430Q542 342 590 392Q617 419 631 471T645 554Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>