<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Sam Feldstein&#39;s Notebook</title>
  <subtitle>Sam Feldstein&#39;s digital notebook.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/" />
  <updated>2025-01-26T23:16:29Z</updated>
  <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Sam Feldstein</name>
    <email>samuelfeldstein@proton.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The Inner Game of Tennis</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/the-inner-game-of-tennis/" />
    <updated>2025-01-26T23:16:29Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/the-inner-game-of-tennis/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allow yourself to discover the &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; that is comfortable for your body and personality and produces effective results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;61&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Serious Man</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/" />
    <updated>2025-01-26T19:17:44Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/a-serious-man/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kindness is often treated as irrational because it isn&#39;t self-interested, and when it comes to passing on genes, self-interest is the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I take more issue with the idea that kindness isn&#39;t self-interested. Of course it is. I&#39;m kind because I&#39;m interested in living in a kind world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t decide if it&#39;s more insulting to suggest that kindness can&#39;t be justified or that it has to be justified in the first place. But here&#39;s what I know: Kindness is good. Can you prove that? I have no idea. I&#39;m not a scientist. But the empirical evidence is roughly on par with the empirical evidence for mortality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;to help another person when we could be taking advantage of them to achieve our own ends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clinical psychologist turned professional asshole Jordan Peterson says that the only proper response to irrational evil is an equally irrational commitment to the &quot;essential goodness of Being.&quot; What I don&#39;t like about these sentiments is that they treat goodness as fundamentally irrational, even silly. And what I appreciate about Judaism is that it teaches us that we can in fact reason our way to good ethics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put reason and ethics at odds does both a disservice. Reason becomes something unethical, and ethics becomes something unreasonable. With respect, this is stupid and also false, and what&#39;s more, I can prove it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The thinking goes since kindness isn&#39;t self-interested, it&#39;s irrational. But who says kindness isn&#39;t interested? I&#39;m kind because I&#39;m interested in living in a kind world. Do I get anything in return for my kindness? Sometimes, sometimes not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;%% Do I need to define my terms? Ethics = kindness? %%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But an action&#39;s reasonability depends on your goal. With regard to morality, reasonability depends on your vision of paradise. If your paradise doesn&#39;t include Jews, Auschwitz becomes a reasonable course of action. %%need another example%%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I think a commitment to goodness is anything &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; irrational.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rational position is one you can explain (&lt;em&gt;explain,&lt;/em&gt; not &lt;em&gt;explain away&lt;/em&gt;), and a commitment to goodness can be easily explained so long as you know what kind of world you&#39;d like to live in. I don&#39;t know about you, but the world I&#39;d like to live in is filled with kind people. If that&#39;s the goal, then it makes sense to be kind. Could you ask for a better rationale?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evil&#39;s prevalence &lt;em&gt;makes&lt;/em&gt; goodness rational.&lt;/strong&gt; Every kindness tips the scales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And even if I can&#39;t find a good reason to be kind, I&#39;ll settle for a good excuse: Kindness makes life better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to make a rational decision, we have to know what kind of world we&#39;re aiming for. That&#39;s easy: It&#39;s the world we want to live in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Good Thinking and Bad Thinking</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/good-thinking-bad-thinking/" />
    <updated>2025-01-25T17:38:46Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/good-thinking-bad-thinking/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good thinking is action unto itself. Bad thinking is all delay (eg, self-doubt).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Advice</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/advice/" />
    <updated>2025-01-25T16:55:47Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/advice/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://paulgraham.com/vb.html&quot;&gt;Avoid bullshit&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; where &quot;bullshit&quot; is anything that completes the sentence &quot;Life is too short for...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://paulgraham.com/vb.html&quot;&gt;Seek out things that matter, and do them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember that most people have to learn what matters to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://danluu.com/p95-skill/&quot;&gt;Get feedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move fast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t think.&lt;/strong&gt; Semantically, this one&#39;s a little confusing. Not all thinking is bad. So you have to distinguish between &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/good-thinking-bad-thinking/&quot;&gt;good thinking and bad thinking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dance as Hedonic Design</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dance-as-hedonic-design/" />
    <updated>2025-01-17T17:28:03Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/dance-as-hedonic-design/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Maverick is a marvel of hedonic design. The ride begins with a literal peak, a 105-foot hill with a 95-degree drop. The track is packed with variators, banks and turns and flips and something called a “twisted horseshoe roll.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then there’s a disruptor: the train comes almost to a standstill inside a tunnel, convincing first-timers that either the ride is over or something’s gone wrong. Then another peak: you suddenly accelerate to 70mph in three seconds, blasting out of the tunnel and into the sky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The finale is a rapid-fire series of banks, spins, and a flight over a canyon where you dodge cannons firing water plumes. The cutoff comes after a mere 150 seconds, just before your brain is totally liquified inside your skull. Recyclers are available as you stagger off the ride: they’ve taken a photo of you screaming your head off, and you can take it home for a mere $20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Adam Mastroianni, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.experimental-history.com/p/the-five-tools-of-hedonic-design?s=w&amp;amp;__readwiseLocation=&quot;&gt;The Five Tools of Hedonic Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dance is a roller coaster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Craft and Purpose</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/craft-and-purpose/" />
    <updated>2025-01-17T16:33:30Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/craft-and-purpose/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can craft itself lend a sense of purpose? I used to think so. I used to think I could derive purpose from making things for the sake of it. Now I think this is wrong. There are plenty of things I like doing and find satisfying. Taking photos, for instance. I like taking photos, and I&#39;m proud of many of the photos I&#39;ve taken. But could I spend all day taking photos and be satisfied? No. Because while I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; photography, I don&#39;t feel that it matters much. The best photographers in the world probably feel differently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So for me, the craft itself doesn&#39;t lend a send of purpose. &lt;strong&gt;The purpose comes from the application of the craft:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;m not coding just to code. I&#39;m coding to build something I can use. I&#39;m not writing just to write. I&#39;m writing to figure something out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, the work itself matters too. I didn&#39;t enjoy helping my mom attach the snowplow to her truck nearly as much as helping her with court case research. &lt;strong&gt;So the work needs to be engaging.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess what you&#39;re looking for is &lt;strong&gt;maximum engagement + maximum importance&lt;/strong&gt;. But in lieu of that ideal situation, &lt;strong&gt;the work either has to be engaging enough to make up for a lack of importance, or important enough to make up for a lack of engagement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, writing fiction isn&#39;t important enough to me to make up how not-engaging it is. By contrast, coding is engaging, but when I do it for anyone other than myself or someone I care about, it doesn&#39;t feel important enough to be worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Easy Hard Work</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/easy-hard-work/" />
    <updated>2025-01-16T18:14:37Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/easy-hard-work/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some types of work are easier than others. Building websites is much easier than writing fiction. It&#39;s not that it&#39;s &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; work, insofar as it&#39;s quite time-consuming, but it&#39;s easier to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; the work. I don&#39;t have to force myself to build websites, at least when I&#39;m doing it for myself. By contrast, I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; had to force myself to write. Building websites is engaging in a way that writing fiction just isn&#39;t. They&#39;re both work. But &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; the work in one case is easy, and in the other the bulk of effort goes to just trying to keep myself at the desk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That sounds pretty good, but I have my doubts. What if some work is just that much harder than other work. I&#39;ve noted before that building websites almost feels like a video game at times, I think because it has a innate feedback loop that writing lacks. You write some code, and the result pops up in the browser. You instantly know if it&#39;s working, and there&#39;s great satisfaction to be taken when it is. Not so with writing. You can only really tell if it&#39;s working once you&#39;ve had some time away from it, and even then it&#39;s not a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But am I taking this feeling for granted? Maybe it&#39;s not the case for everyone. And if it&#39;s not, then shouldn&#39;t be take our kicks where we get them? If someone else described cooking the same way, I wouldn&#39;t be able to agree. Cooking is fun and satisyfing, but not nearly as engaging as coding. But if someone found cooking as engaging as I find coding, I&#39;d say that person is cut out to be a chef.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But still, it&#39;s not that simple. Because I only find coding that engaging when I care about the project. I had fun builidng my personal site. Likewise with my mom&#39;s website. But my freelance gigs aren&#39;t nearly as fun, and I think this is because I just don&#39;t care as much. The emotional investment isn&#39;t there. Which tells that the emotional investment is necessary to doing good work. That might seem obvious, but I&#39;ve also spent a lot of time trying to detach myself emotionally from a given project becasue I was convinced that toom uch investment was a bad thing, because it tied too much of your self worth to the project and so engendered self-consciousness. If I could just become a stoic craftsman, then maybe I could do something interseting, free from fear and doubt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There might be something to that, and I doubt there&#39;s one way to go about it. Probably you just have to find the thing that works for you. If you can&#39;t get there without the emotional volatility, embrace it. If you can only get there by quashing the feelings, crush them mercilessly. Usually you can do this with another feeling. Quash doubt with anger, for instance. That takes an immense amount of effort, which is probably why writing is so exhausting. You&#39;re trying to keep a lid on the self-doubt while perfecting a craft at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is why people like Ray Bradbury tell you not to think. Stephen King says to write fast enough to outrun the self doubt. Another way to think about it is to do your best to try to get absorbed in the work to such a degree that you and your feelinsg disappers, and all that&#39;s left is the work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which comes back to engagement. The more engaging work is, the easier it is to fall into it, so to speak. But choosing activities solely based on how engaging they are seemsl ike a bad idea. If you did that, you&#39;d just play video games all day. That said, I don&#39;t find video games nearly as engaging as I used to. So this, like all things, seems subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The broader question though is is it wrong to choose work based on how engaging it is? Am I wrong to choose websites over writing because I find building websites so much more engaging than writing? I don&#39;t see why that should be a problem. If you can find something useful to do that you don&#39;t have to force yousrelf to do, that seems like as close a recipe to career happiness as you can get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But it&#39;s multivariate. The work either has to be engaging enough or important enough to make up for it. Writing simply isn&#39;t important enough to me to make up how not engaging it is. Coding is engaging, but when I do for anyone other than myself or someone I care about, suddenly it&#39;s not important enough to be worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s why I want to work for myself. Maybe I&#39;m selfish, but I find it very difficult to summon the will to work for other people. I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it. I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; done it. And I&#39;ve worked hard. But it&#39;s no way to spend a life. The solution is to work for myself, or possibly with a friend. I&#39;m pretty sure that&#39;s as close to a satisfying career as I&#39;m ever going to get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective Learning</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/learning/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T20:51:39Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/learning/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo_Guru&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Self-Hatred</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/self-hatred/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T06:18:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/self-hatred/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hated myself for the first twenty-five years of my life, give or take. (I still do sometimes, but it&#39;s &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better.) I thought I was pathetic. I struggled to do things that in my imagination came naturally to other people. Talking to girls, for instance. Or talking to anybody, for that matter. For years, I could not for the life of me hold a conversation. I tried to pay attention, to come up with interesting things to say, but inevitably I&#39;d feel the conversation dying on the vine and I&#39;d know it was my fault and I wouldn&#39;t mean to but I couldn&#39;t help but kill it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried to study other people and how they talked to each other, though I don&#39;t think I did it with a critical eye so much as an envious one, thinking to myself &lt;em&gt;I wish I could do that. What&#39;s wrong with me that I can&#39;t?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&#39;re allowed to have a low opinion of yourself as long as you come by it honestly.&lt;/strong&gt; But at some point self-pity becomes self-serving. It gives you an out. I can&#39;t be bothered to put in the effort? Great, I&#39;m too stupid to figure it out anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Discomfort</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/discomfort/" />
    <updated>2025-01-15T06:07:21Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/discomfort/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always stayed in my comfort zone. I never did anything hard, out of some combination of fear and laziness. I never liked that about myself, but it took me a long time to do anything about it. I basically spent the first twenty-five years of my life working up the nerve to do anything interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost every decision I&#39;ve made in the last year (Workaway, taking up dance) has been a direct assault on my lack of confidence. This is a theme for me. &lt;strong&gt;Pretty much every real decision I&#39;ve made I&#39;ve made out of a desire to change something I don&#39;t like about myself.&lt;/strong&gt; And I have to say, I&#39;m pretty happy with the person I&#39;ve become in the last two years. He&#39;s much more confident than he used to be. He&#39;s friendly. He&#39;s learned, somewhat, how to set the tone of an interaction. He&#39;s learned to become aware of other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>