<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Sam Feldstein&#39;s Notebook</title>
  <subtitle>Sam Feldstein&#39;s digital notebook.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/" />
  <updated>2025-01-14T20:55:25Z</updated>
  <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Sam Feldstein</name>
    <email>samuelfeldstein@proton.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Judaism Resources</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/judaism-resources/" />
    <updated>2025-01-14T20:55:25Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/judaism-resources/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://jeffbenner.net&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Honesty</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/honesty/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T21:52:33Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/honesty/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you never piss anyone off, you probably aren&#39;t speaking your mind enough. (That said, I don&#39;t admire people who enjoy pissing people off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you aren&#39;t honest, you&#39;ll never connect with people the way you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>On Purpose</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/on-purpose/" />
    <updated>2025-01-13T19:14:09Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/on-purpose/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;style id=&quot;MJX-SVG-styles&quot;&gt;
mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] {
  direction: ltr;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] &gt; svg {
  overflow: visible;
  min-height: 1px;
  min-width: 1px;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] &gt; svg a {
  fill: blue;
  stroke: blue;
}

mjx-assistive-mml {
  position: absolute !important;
  top: 0px;
  left: 0px;
  clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);
  padding: 1px 0px 0px 0px !important;
  border: 0px !important;
  display: block !important;
  width: auto !important;
  overflow: hidden !important;
  -webkit-touch-callout: none;
  -webkit-user-select: none;
  -khtml-user-select: none;
  -moz-user-select: none;
  -ms-user-select: none;
  user-select: none;
}

mjx-assistive-mml[display=&quot;block&quot;] {
  width: 100% !important;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][display=&quot;true&quot;] {
  display: block;
  text-align: center;
  margin: 1em 0;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][display=&quot;true&quot;][width=&quot;full&quot;] {
  display: flex;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][justify=&quot;left&quot;] {
  text-align: left;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;][justify=&quot;right&quot;] {
  text-align: right;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;merror&quot;] &gt; g {
  fill: red;
  stroke: red;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;merror&quot;] &gt; rect[data-background] {
  fill: yellow;
  stroke: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; line[data-line], svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; line[data-line] {
  stroke-width: 70px;
  fill: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; rect[data-frame], svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; rect[data-frame] {
  stroke-width: 70px;
  fill: none;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; .mjx-dashed, svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; .mjx-dashed {
  stroke-dasharray: 140;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; .mjx-dotted, svg[data-table] &gt; g &gt; .mjx-dotted {
  stroke-linecap: round;
  stroke-dasharray: 0,140;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;mtable&quot;] &gt; g &gt; svg {
  overflow: visible;
}

[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] mjx-tool {
  display: inline-block;
  position: relative;
  width: 0;
  height: 0;
}

[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] mjx-tool &gt; mjx-tip {
  position: absolute;
  top: 0;
  left: 0;
}

mjx-tool &gt; mjx-tip {
  display: inline-block;
  padding: .2em;
  border: 1px solid #888;
  font-size: 70%;
  background-color: #F8F8F8;
  color: black;
  box-shadow: 2px 2px 5px #AAAAAA;
}

g[data-mml-node=&quot;maction&quot;][data-toggle] {
  cursor: pointer;
}

mjx-status {
  display: block;
  position: fixed;
  left: 1em;
  bottom: 1em;
  min-width: 25%;
  padding: .2em .4em;
  border: 1px solid #888;
  font-size: 90%;
  background-color: #F8F8F8;
  color: black;
}

foreignObject[data-mjx-xml] {
  font-family: initial;
  line-height: normal;
  overflow: visible;
}

mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] path[data-c], mjx-container[jax=&quot;SVG&quot;] use[data-c] {
  stroke-width: 3;
}
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To live a fulfilling life, you need a sense of purpose.&lt;/strong&gt; I think this is what people mean when they talk about &quot;finding their place in the world&quot; or living a &quot;meaningful&quot; life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s a sense of purpose? A feeling that you matter? That you&#39;ve made a difference? I suppose this depends on the person, so all I can do here is answer for myself. &lt;strong&gt;So for me, a sense of purpose is a sense that I&#39;ve made a difference, that I&#39;ve done something that matters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where do we find purpose?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think I could derive purpose from craft, from making things. Now I think this is wrong. There are plenty of things I like doing and find satisfying. Taking photos, for instance. I like taking photos, and I&#39;m proud of many of the photos I&#39;ve taken. But could I spend all day taking photos and be satisfied? No. Because while I &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; photography, I don&#39;t feel that it matters much. It doesn&#39;t give me a sense of purpose. The best photographers in the world probably feel differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for me, the craft itself doesn&#39;t lend a send of purpose. &lt;strong&gt;The purpose comes from the application of the craft:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;m not coding just to code. I&#39;m coding to build something I can use. I&#39;m not writing just to write. I&#39;m writing to figure something out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; I get that feeling of purpose? When have I felt that? Here&#39;s a list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I helped my mom research a court case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I&#39;ve helped new dancers learn the basics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I organized a writers&#39; group in grad school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I&#39;ve given feedback on friends&#39; writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I taught horseback riding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things all involve working with people. &lt;strong&gt;More specifically, they all seem to involve collaboration.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of them involve some individual work (eg, researching a court case), but in service to a collaborative project. Teaching, when done right, is a kind of collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of each collaboration seems to serve the other person. &lt;strong&gt;So it seems that I prefer helping to being helped.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure whether this would translate to collaborating in service to a mutual goal (eg, cofounding a company). I haven&#39;t done much of that. But I&#39;m curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these (writers group) involves community-building. Haven&#39;t done much of that either. I do like hosting parties, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The work matters too.&lt;/strong&gt; I didn&#39;t enjoy helping my mom attach the snowplow to her truck nearly as much as helping her with the court case research. &lt;strong&gt;So the work needs to be engaging.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe the formula is something like: &lt;em&gt;Engaging work + helping + a useful application = a sense of purpose.&lt;/em&gt; Or:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;mjx-container class=&quot;MathJax&quot; jax=&quot;SVG&quot; style=&quot;position: relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg style=&quot;vertical-align: -0.186ex;&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;15.682ex&quot; height=&quot;1.805ex&quot; role=&quot;img&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 -716 6931.4 798&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;currentColor&quot; fill=&quot;currentColor&quot; stroke-width=&quot;0&quot; transform=&quot;scale(1,-1)&quot;&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;math&quot;&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D438&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D438&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(986.2,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;2B&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(1986.4,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D43B&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D43B&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(3096.7,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;2B&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(4096.9,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D434&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D434&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mo&quot; transform=&quot;translate(5124.7,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;3D&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-N-3D&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;g data-mml-node=&quot;mi&quot; transform=&quot;translate(6180.4,0)&quot;&gt;&lt;use data-c=&quot;1D443&quot; xlink:href=&quot;#MJX-TEX-I-1D443&quot;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;mjx-assistive-mml unselectable=&quot;on&quot; display=&quot;inline&quot;&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;&lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;H&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;/math&gt;&lt;/mjx-assistive-mml&gt;&lt;/mjx-container&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we be sure we&#39;ll know it when we see it? I doubt it will be so epiphanic. It takes time to get comfortable with anything, and so even if you are currently occupying what will eventually become your place in the world, you may not be comfortable enough to realize it. And if you don&#39;t put in the time and effort, your place will never become your place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there are people who describe it this way. They looked around, tried things, and found something they loved doing so much that it became obvious that that was their calling. But these people are the minority. How many people like that do you know personally?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have to look around, which takes time, but also if you&#39;re going to find your place, you&#39;re going to have to devote a certain amount of time to that place if anything is going to come of it. It&#39;s a dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t pretend to have the answers. And I suppose I&#39;ll only get the answers when and if I do find my place in the world. Until then, I&#39;ll have to get used to being uncomfortable. Which I&#39;m okay at. I&#39;ve always stuck to my comfort zone. I never wanted to do anything hard. I&#39;m fundamentally scared and lazy, and this has held me back my whole life. I don&#39;t mean to pass the buck. It&#39;s my personality, my responsibiliy. But it&#39;s only lately that I&#39;ve really tried to do anhthing about it. I guess I have done things about it my whole life, though it wouldn&#39;t look that way from the outside. Internally, probably what that looks like is me spending the first twenty-five years of my life working up the nerve to do anything interesting or discomfiting. Almost every decision I&#39;ve made in the last year has been a direct assault on my lack of confidence. Traveling solo, for instance. I knew I could, but I needed to prove it. I doubt that will be the last time I do such a thing, because if I can&#39;t be doing something important I may as well be doing something interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dancing was another way I attacked my low self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I realize that all of this makes me fundamentally pathetic. I struggle to do things that in my imagination most people have been doing their whole lives. Asking women on dates, for instance. I think I&#39;ve probably done this three times in my life. The reason I&#39;m so far behind is that I struggle to be a person in ways that seem to come naturally to other people. I didn&#39;t know how to hold a conversation for years, and this is seomthing I still struggle with. I try to pay attention, to talk, but I can feel the conversation dying and I know it&#39;s my fault and I don&#39;t mean to but I can&#39;t help it. It&#39;s like I&#39;m strangling it to death on accident. And I&#39;ve always been like this. I&#39;ve tried to study other people and how they talk to each other, though I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve done so with much of a critical eye. MOre of an envious one, thinking &lt;em&gt;I wish I could do that. What&#39;s wrong with me that I can&#39;t?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this kind of self-pity is dangerous. It&#39;s dnagerous because it&#39;s self-serving. It gives you an out. I&#39;ve known this for a long time, and for a long time I haven&#39;t done anything about it even though I&#39;ve wanted to. Hence the travel and the dance. If I can do those things, then I&#39;m kind of person who does those things. And the kinds of people who do those things are cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is entirely possible that my priorities are completely out of whack here. They usually are. But I have to admit that in a lot of ways I&#39;m happy with the person I&#39;ve become in the last two years. He&#39;s much more confident than he used to be. He&#39;s friendly. He&#39;s learned, somewhat, how to set the tone of an interaction. He&#39;s learned to become aware of other people and in so doing become less aware of himself. Or rather, to be aware of himself as part of the world instead of an island within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spent the last two years learning how to be a person. I don&#39;t what I was doing the rest of the time. Nothing particuarly interesting. Not building a career, that&#39;s for sure. I hate to think that it was time wasted, and not 100% of it was, of course. But a lot of it was. A lot of it was spent trying to force myseelf to write when I didn&#39;t want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&#39;s hard to know where to draw that line. At what point do you accept that something is hard, and do the work anything because it&#39;s worth it? And at what point do you realize that the reason the work is hard is that you don&#39;t actually like it very much?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve found that some work is easier than others. I&#39;ve drawn this comparison before, but building websites (to me) is much easiser than writing fiction. It&#39;s not that it&#39;s less work, insofar as it&#39;s quite time-consuming, but the difference lies in how easy it is to &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; the work. I don&#39;t have to force myself to build websites, at least when I&#39;m doing it for myself. By contrast, I &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; had to force myself to write. Building websites is engaging in a way that writing fiction simply isn&#39;t. They&#39;re both work. But &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; the work in one case is easy, and in the other the bulk of effort goes to just trying to keep myself at the desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sounds pretty good, but I have my doubts. What if some work is just that much harder than other work. I&#39;ve noted before that building websites almost feels like a video game at times, I think because it has a innate feedback loop that writing lacks. You write some code, and the result pops up in the browser. You instantly know if it&#39;s working, and there&#39;s great satisfaction to be taken when it is. Not so with writing. You can only really tell if it&#39;s working once you&#39;ve had some time away from it, and even then it&#39;s not a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But am I taking this feeling for granted? Maybe it&#39;s not the case for everyone. And if it&#39;s not, then shouldn&#39;t be take our kicks where we get them? If someone else described cooking the same way, I wouldn&#39;t be able to agree. Cooking is fun and satisyfing, but not nearly as engaging as coding. But if someone found cooking as engaging as I find coding, I&#39;d say that person is cut out to be a chef.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, it&#39;s not that simple. Because I only find coding that engaging when I care about the project. I had fun builidng my personal site. Likewise with my mom&#39;s website. But my freelance gigs aren&#39;t nearly as fun, and I think this is because I just don&#39;t care as much. The emotional investment isn&#39;t there. Which tells that the emotional investment is necessary to doing good work. That might seem obvious, but I&#39;ve also spent a lot of time trying to detach myself emotionally from a given project becasue I was convinced that toom uch investment was a bad thing, because it tied too much of your self worth to the project and so engendered self-consciousness. If I could just become a stoic craftsman, then maybe I could do something interseting, free from fear and doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be something to that, and I doubt there&#39;s one way to go about it. Probably you just have to find the thing that works for you. If you can&#39;t get there without the emotional volatility, embrace it. If you can only get there by quashing the feelings, crush them mercilessly. Usually you can do this with another feeling. Quash doubt with anger, for instance. That takes an immense amount of effort, which is probably why writing is so exhausting. You&#39;re trying to keep a lid on the self-doubt while perfecting a craft at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why people like Ray Bradbury tell you not to think. Stephen King says to write fast enough to outrun the self doubt. Another way to think about it is to do your best to try to get absorbed in the work to such a degree that you and your feelinsg disappers, and all that&#39;s left is the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which comes back to engagement. The more engaging work is, the easier it is to fall into it, so to speak. But choosing activities solely based on how engaging they are seemsl ike a bad idea. If you did that, you&#39;d just play video games all day. That said, I don&#39;t find video games nearly as engaging as I used to. So this, like all things, seems subject to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The broader question though is is it wrong to choose work based on how engaging it is? Am I wrong to choose websites over writing because I find building websites so much more engaging than writing? I don&#39;t see why that should be a problem. If you can find something useful to do that you don&#39;t have to force yousrelf to do, that seems like as close a recipe to career happiness as you can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&#39;s multivariate. The work either has to be engaging enough or important enough to make up for it. Writing simply isn&#39;t important enough to me to make up how not engaging it is. Coding is engaging, but when I do for anyone other than myself or someone I care about, suddnely it&#39;s not important enough to be worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s why I want to work for myself. Maybe I&#39;m selfish, but I find it very difficult to summon the will to work for other people. I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do it. I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; done it. And I&#39;ve worked hard. But it&#39;s no way to spend a life. The solution is to work for myself, or possibly with a friend. I&#39;m pretty sure that&#39;s as close to a satisfying career as I&#39;m ever going to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could make some money with some of these things. You could open a coffee shop or a dance studio. You could open an online boutique selling personal little sites. The first two are out of the question; I don&#39;t have the money or the expertise, and anyway the margins on coffee probably aren&#39;t worth the startup cost. I do plan to open that online boutique someday soon, if I can figure out how to minimize the workload such that I can charge a reasonable rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s career as distinct from life. This is a common dichotomy. Everybody understands it. You work a job you don&#39;t like to make money so you can afford to do the things you do like. Ideally, you find work you like doing enough that you don&#39;t feel the need to draw that dichotomy. The only way I see that happening for me is if I start my own business. Because if I&#39;m working for a boss, or even for freelance clients, that dichotomy is always going to be there because work is always going to be something to escape. The line is drawn by relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you work for yourself, running a business for instance, than it becomse another activity you enjoy. Just one where you&#39;re making money. The hard line between work and life starts to fade, and then it&#39;s just life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to make money. Sell your time or a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the risk of being self-indulgent, it might be interesting to survey family and friends and see what they think you&#39;re good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;svg style=&quot;display: none;&quot; id=&quot;MJX-SVG-global-cache&quot;&gt;&lt;defs&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D438&quot; d=&quot;M492 213Q472 213 472 226Q472 230 477 250T482 285Q482 316 461 323T364 330H312Q311 328 277 192T243 52Q243 48 254 48T334 46Q428 46 458 48T518 61Q567 77 599 117T670 248Q680 270 683 272Q690 274 698 274Q718 274 718 261Q613 7 608 2Q605 0 322 0H133Q31 0 31 11Q31 13 34 25Q38 41 42 43T65 46Q92 46 125 49Q139 52 144 61Q146 66 215 342T285 622Q285 629 281 629Q273 632 228 634H197Q191 640 191 642T193 659Q197 676 203 680H757Q764 676 764 669Q764 664 751 557T737 447Q735 440 717 440H705Q698 445 698 453L701 476Q704 500 704 528Q704 558 697 578T678 609T643 625T596 632T532 634H485Q397 633 392 631Q388 629 386 622Q385 619 355 499T324 377Q347 376 372 376H398Q464 376 489 391T534 472Q538 488 540 490T557 493Q562 493 565 493T570 492T572 491T574 487T577 483L544 351Q511 218 508 216Q505 213 492 213Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-N-2B&quot; d=&quot;M56 237T56 250T70 270H369V420L370 570Q380 583 389 583Q402 583 409 568V270H707Q722 262 722 250T707 230H409V-68Q401 -82 391 -82H389H387Q375 -82 369 -68V230H70Q56 237 56 250Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D43B&quot; d=&quot;M228 637Q194 637 192 641Q191 643 191 649Q191 673 202 682Q204 683 219 683Q260 681 355 681Q389 681 418 681T463 682T483 682Q499 682 499 672Q499 670 497 658Q492 641 487 638H485Q483 638 480 638T473 638T464 637T455 637Q416 636 405 634T387 623Q384 619 355 500Q348 474 340 442T328 395L324 380Q324 378 469 378H614L615 381Q615 384 646 504Q674 619 674 627T617 637Q594 637 587 639T580 648Q580 650 582 660Q586 677 588 679T604 682Q609 682 646 681T740 680Q802 680 835 681T871 682Q888 682 888 672Q888 645 876 638H874Q872 638 869 638T862 638T853 637T844 637Q805 636 794 634T776 623Q773 618 704 340T634 58Q634 51 638 51Q646 48 692 46H723Q729 38 729 37T726 19Q722 6 716 0H701Q664 2 567 2Q533 2 504 2T458 2T437 1Q420 1 420 10Q420 15 423 24Q428 43 433 45Q437 46 448 46H454Q481 46 514 49Q520 50 522 50T528 55T534 64T540 82T547 110T558 153Q565 181 569 198Q602 330 602 331T457 332H312L279 197Q245 63 245 58Q245 51 253 49T303 46H334Q340 38 340 37T337 19Q333 6 327 0H312Q275 2 178 2Q144 2 115 2T69 2T48 1Q31 1 31 10Q31 12 34 24Q39 43 44 45Q48 46 59 46H65Q92 46 125 49Q139 52 144 61Q147 65 216 339T285 628Q285 635 228 637Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D434&quot; d=&quot;M208 74Q208 50 254 46Q272 46 272 35Q272 34 270 22Q267 8 264 4T251 0Q249 0 239 0T205 1T141 2Q70 2 50 0H42Q35 7 35 11Q37 38 48 46H62Q132 49 164 96Q170 102 345 401T523 704Q530 716 547 716H555H572Q578 707 578 706L606 383Q634 60 636 57Q641 46 701 46Q726 46 726 36Q726 34 723 22Q720 7 718 4T704 0Q701 0 690 0T651 1T578 2Q484 2 455 0H443Q437 6 437 9T439 27Q443 40 445 43L449 46H469Q523 49 533 63L521 213H283L249 155Q208 86 208 74ZM516 260Q516 271 504 416T490 562L463 519Q447 492 400 412L310 260L413 259Q516 259 516 260Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-N-3D&quot; d=&quot;M56 347Q56 360 70 367H707Q722 359 722 347Q722 336 708 328L390 327H72Q56 332 56 347ZM56 153Q56 168 72 173H708Q722 163 722 153Q722 140 707 133H70Q56 140 56 153Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;path id=&quot;MJX-TEX-I-1D443&quot; d=&quot;M287 628Q287 635 230 637Q206 637 199 638T192 648Q192 649 194 659Q200 679 203 681T397 683Q587 682 600 680Q664 669 707 631T751 530Q751 453 685 389Q616 321 507 303Q500 302 402 301H307L277 182Q247 66 247 59Q247 55 248 54T255 50T272 48T305 46H336Q342 37 342 35Q342 19 335 5Q330 0 319 0Q316 0 282 1T182 2Q120 2 87 2T51 1Q33 1 33 11Q33 13 36 25Q40 41 44 43T67 46Q94 46 127 49Q141 52 146 61Q149 65 218 339T287 628ZM645 554Q645 567 643 575T634 597T609 619T560 635Q553 636 480 637Q463 637 445 637T416 636T404 636Q391 635 386 627Q384 621 367 550T332 412T314 344Q314 342 395 342H407H430Q542 342 590 392Q617 419 631 471T645 554Z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Open Graph Markup</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/open-graph-markup/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T19:24:13Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/open-graph-markup/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure page titles are descriptive, descriptions are thorough, and everything is unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ogp.me&quot;&gt;Open Graph Markup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Analogies</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/analogies/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T17:39:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/analogies/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analogies work by taking two ideas that appear very different and revealing a significant similarity. The more different the two objects are, the more the similarity will stick out, and the harder the point will be hammered home. &lt;strong&gt;So the more dissimilar the objects, the better?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Learning Paradox</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/the-learning-paradox/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T17:08:31Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/the-learning-paradox/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might learn a new word, but &lt;strong&gt;you won&#39;t really know how to use it until you get a feel for it, and you won&#39;t get a feel for it until you use it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure how interesting this is. It seems like a common enough phenomenon that I thought surely there must be a name for it. But the closest thing I&#39;ve found is the &quot;entry level job paradox:&quot; &lt;strong&gt;You need experience to get a job, but you can&#39;t get a job without experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, I think the lesson here is that can&#39;t get good at things without doing them, which means you have to start doing things before you&#39;re good at them. In other words, &lt;strong&gt;mistakes are an inevitable and therefore necessary part of the learning process&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If mistakes are inevitable, that makes trying to avoid them futile and a waste of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Media</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/social-media/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T17:06:33Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/social-media/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;https://thread-splitter.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Definitions</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/definitions/" />
    <updated>2025-01-10T16:41:29Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/definitions/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions are approximations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions are keys?&lt;/strong&gt; Keys to a room, and inside the room is the concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Or maybe they&#39;re buttons&lt;/strong&gt;. When pushed, they activate knowledge.w&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Video Games That Might Teach You Something</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/video-games-that-might-teach-you-something/" />
    <updated>2025-01-04T18:53:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/video-games-that-might-teach-you-something/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveonline.com&quot;&gt;https://www.eveonline.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sim City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Search Engine Optimization</title>
    <link href="https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/seo/" />
    <updated>2025-01-03T04:04:50Z</updated>
    <id>https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/seo/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the site is &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/how-to-improve-website-performance/&quot;&gt;performant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/appearance/structured-data/intro-structured-data&quot;&gt;structured data&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://validator.schema.org&quot;&gt;Validate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;a href=&quot;https://notebook.samfeldstein.xyz/notes/open-graph-markup/&quot;&gt;Open Graph Markup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/crawling-indexing/sitemaps/overview&quot;&gt;sitemap&lt;/a&gt; to search engines. Google and Bing are really the only two to worry about, I think. There&#39;s Yahoo, I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/crawling-indexing/ask-google-to-recrawl&quot;&gt;Request indexing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>